A Guide to the Sonner Family Papers, 1772-1846
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Sonner Family Papers, 1772-1846
The Library of Virginia
22552
2 leaves and 25 pages
Sonner Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 16 August 1946, of Samuel L. Burgess.
Biographical Information
John Philip Sonner was born in 1736 in Wurttenburg, Germany, and emigrated to Philadlphia, Pennsylvania, about 1753. By 1757, he had moved to Frederick County, Virginia, and settled near what is now Strasburg, Shenandoah County, Virginia. A weaver by trade in Germany, he became a farmer in Virginia. He married first, Christena Windle (ca. 1739-1787) in Frederick County in 1759, and they had 8 children. Sonner married second, Frany Hiser 4 March 1788. Jacob Sonner (1766-1837) was Johan Philip Sonner's son. A farmer like his father, Jacob Sonner also served as constable of Shenandoah County. He married first, Rebecca Harriet Copenhaver 10 February 1795. He married second, Catherine Hiser 1 July 1813, and they had 5 children. Henry Sonner (1817-1858) and Samuel Harrison Sonner (1821-1901) were their sons.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1772-1846, of the Sonner family of Shenandoah County, Virginia, consisting of land grants and deeds, 1772-1846, for real property in Frederick and Shenandoah Counties, and Strasburg, Virginia. Also includes a notice, dated 11 August 1823, of public sales to be held to satisfy court executions from Jacob Sonner, constable.
Contents List
- Grant, 7 January 1772, for 323 acres in Frederick County, Virginia, from Thomas Lord Fairfax (1693-1781) to Johan Philip Sonner (1736-1806).
- Grant, 11 January 1772, for 302 acres in Frederick County from Fairfax to Sonner.
- Deed, dated 11 March 1783 and recorded 27 March 1783, for lot number 78 in the town of Starsburg (Strasburg) from Peter Stover (1720-1799) and Frainey Stover (b. ca. 1728) to Samuel Bowman (d. ca. 1799), all of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 13 November 1796 and recorded 11 April 1797, for lot number 78 in Strasburg from Jacob Backer to Jacob Sonner (1766-1837), both of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 3 April 1799 and recorded 9 July 1799, for 1/2 acre in lot number 46 in Strasburg from Jacob Funk (d. 1847) and Catherina Funk (1763-1846) to Jacob Sonner, all of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 22 May 1799 and recorded 10 September 1799, for lot number 74 in Strasburg from Joseph Stover (ca. 1752-1819) to Jacob Sonner, both of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 2 April 1803 and recorded 10 June 1805, for lot number 74 in Strasburg from Jacob Funk and Catherina Funk to Jacob Sonner.
- Notice, 11 August 1823, of public sales to be held to satisfy court executions from Jacob Sonner, constable.
- Deed, dated 3 September 1831 and recorded 10 October 1831, for 1/2 of lot number 31 in Strasburg from Isaac Conrad and Mary Conrad, Thomas Longhade and Rebecca Ann Longhade of Frederick County, George Conrad and Mary Ann Conrad of Culpeper County, Virginia, Maria Conrad, John Dosh (d. 1844) and Catherine Dosh of Shenandoah County, all heirs of Joseph Conrad, to Jacob Sonner.
- Deed, 17 February 1835, for 9 acres in Shenandoah County from Jacob Sonner to Wright Gatewood (1795-1882), both of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 28 March 1846 and recorded 13 April 1846, for 54 acres in Shenandoah County from Henry Sonner (1817-1858) and Jane Sonner (1821-1898) to Samuel Harrison Sonner (1821-1901), all of Shenandoah County.